[{"question":"<p><strong>When Nigeria achieved Independence in 1960, the Head of State was the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Governor-General","Prime Minister","Queen of England","President"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first restructuring of the Nigerian Federation took place with the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["military counter-coup of 1966","creation of states in 1967","abolition of federalism in 1966","the creation of the Mid-West Region in 1963"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the parliamentary system, the term shadow cabinet is often used to refer to the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["back-benchers in the house","deputy prime ministers and assistant ministers","rebellious members of the ruling party","portfolio designated of the party in opposition"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>Acculturation in colonial administration was associated with the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["French policy of assimilation","British policy of direct rule","French policy of association","British indirect rule system."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>An example of promotional pressure group is the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Supreme Council of Islamic Affairs","Nigerian Medical Association","Civil Liberties Organization","Manufacturers Association of Nigeria"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>The breakdown of the Macpherson Constitution was partly caused by the crisis within the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["NCNC","AG","NPC","NNDP"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria is the major shareholder in the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["OPEC fund for development","African development bank","World bank","International monetary fund"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>The official report of proceedings in parliament is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["hansard","diary of events","gazette","summary of proceedings"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 1946 Constitution was remarkable because it<\/strong><\/p>","options":["created ministerial positions in Nigeria.","introduced regional governments in Nigeria.","introduced for the first time the elective principle","brought about self-government for Nigeria"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>The British Government&nbsp; revoked the Charter of the Royal Niger Company and took over the administration of Nigeria in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1861","1885","1900","1944"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>&nbsp;In Nigeria, the Local Government Service Commission is set up by the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["local government chairman","federal government","local government councils","state government"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>The head of Commonwealth of Nations is the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["chairman of the conference of the Commonwealth Heads of Governments","Queen of Great Britain","Prime Minister of Great Britain","Secretary-General of the Commonwealth"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>Southern Nigeria was divided into Eastern and Western Provinces for administrative purposes in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1935","1937","1939","1941"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>The OAU was founded on the principles of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["settlement of international disputes by armed struggle","justifiable interferences in the domestic affairs of member states","sovereign equality of member states","equal contribution by member states"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2017"},{"question":"<p><strong>Case-laws are made by the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Judiciary","President","Executive","Legislature"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The two leaders that played the most prominent roles in the formation of the ECOWAS were&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Acheampong and Jawara","Gowon and Eyadema","Kerekou and Tubman","Kounche and Senghor"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The political party with the widest spread of membership in Nigeria during the Second Republic was the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["GNPP","UPN","NPP","NPN"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Aro system in Igboland was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a political organization","a commercial organization","a religious organization","an imperial organization"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following had a centralized administration in pre-colonial Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Igbos","The Tivs","The Ibibios","The Yorubas"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following organs control the Civil Service?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Parliament and the Courts","Trade unions and the courts","The police and parliament","Tribunals and interest groups"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The expenditure of public funds by the executive in Nigeria is controlled by the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["legislature","judiciary","president","ministry of finance"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the Igbo political system, authority was shared among<\/strong><\/p>","options":["men and women with ozo titles","all age groups and warrant chiefs","elders of the community and ofo title holders","title holders and age groups"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A popular principle of colonial administration in British West Africa was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["association","indirect rule","assimilation","westernization"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The crucial check on the autocratic oba in the pre-colonial Yoruba political system was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["presenting to him a suicide symbol","avoiding the palace","sending him on exile","refusing to carry out his orders."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>According to Aristole, a form of government in which the few rule for the benefit of all is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["diarchy","aristocracy","autocracy","polyarchy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following bodies is the most representative organ of the United Nations?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Security Council","The Trusteeship Council","The General Assembly","The Economic and Social Council"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The pre-colonial Tiv society can best be described as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["republican","aristocratic","feudalistic","monarchical"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The major function of the civil service is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["providing relevant information on government","keeping records of the activities of government","promoting the interest of civil servants","advising government and implement his policies"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is a feature of democracy?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Power vested in minority parties","Popular consultation","Interdependence of states","State responsibilities to society"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the distinctive features of one party system is that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the ruling party is the only legal party","communism is banned","the communist party is the only legal party","elections to the legislature are held at the party's conferences"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The principle of anonymity of civil servants means that they<\/strong><\/p>","options":["have a career","are not the servant of a particular government","are trained for the duties they performed","are credited or blamed for anything they do"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>First Governor-General of colonial Nigeria was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Lord Lugard","Dr. Nnamdi Azikwe","Sir James Robertson","Sir Hugh Clifford"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The major innovation of the Republican constitution of 1963 was that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the Prime Minister ceased to be Head of State","the Governor's office as the representative of the queen was abolished","the Cabinet was no longer responsible to the legislature","it introduced the Executive Presidential System"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>A fascist regime is both<\/strong><\/p>","options":["authoritarian and totalitarian","fair and legitimate","democratic and constitutional","representative and accountable"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the presidential system of government, ministers are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["individually responsible to the president","collectively responsible to the president","individually responsible to no one","collectively responsible to the senate"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Red-tapism in the civil service refers to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the use of red tapes on documents","slowness of action","the cooperation between civil servants and politicians","politicization of civil service"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 1953 motion that Nigeria should become independent in 1956 was moved by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chief Anthony Enaharo","Sir Ahmadu Bello","Chief Obafemi Awolowo","Dr. Nnamdi Azikiwe"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT an organ of OAU?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The Economic Commission for Africa","The Council of Ministers","The Commission for Mediation, Conciliation and Arbitration","The Assembly of Heads of States and Government"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Yoruba traditional government system was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["egalitarian","democratic","republican","monarchical"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Under what constitution did the Supreme Court become the highest Court of Appeal in Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Macpherson's Constitution","Clifford's Constitution","Richard's Constitution","The 1963 Constitution"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The agency responsible for investigation allegations of mal-administration in the civil service is the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Federal Service Commission","Code of Conduct Bureau","Public Complaints Commission","Federal Character Commission"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>A proclamation by the Head of Sate ending a session of parliament is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a dissolution","an adjournment","a prorogation","an abrogation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 1963 Constitution in Nigeria is known as the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Presidential Constitution","Independence Constitution","Republican Constitution","Federal Constitution"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Nigeria, the institution that preserves civil liberty is the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Public Complaints Commission","Federal Electoral Commission","Law Court","National Security Organization"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bill can become law only after the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["final reading","presidential assent","third reading","committee stage"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Local governments in Nigeria are in order to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["create more civil service jobs","encourage competitions and rivalry among group","bring the government nearer to the people","prevent the creation of more states"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The day-to-day operation of public corporation is the direct responsibility of the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["management","union workers","supervising ministry","board of directors"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a parliamentary system, powers of the organs of government are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["diffused","separated","fused","divided"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a public corporation in Nigeria<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Joint Admission and Matriculations Board","Nigerian Steel Development Authority","Nigerian National Shipping Line","Nigerian Railway Corporation"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>'Pacification' refers to the process through which some areas in Nigerian were acquired by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["military conquest","gunboat diplomacy","signing of treaties","peaceful negotiation"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A Unitary System of Government leads to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["too much expenditure","duplication of resources","delay in passage of bills","quick passage of bills"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The primary objective of privatization policy in Nigeria is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["probity","responsiveness","transparency","accountability"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Delegation is necessary because<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the parliament has enough time","the parliament has all the expertise","some bills are technical in nature","some bills are easy to handle"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Prior to 1966, the system of local government in the Western Region was based on the three-tier structure of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["native authority, division and district councils","district, local and area councils","division, district and local councils","province, district and local councils"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following was NOT the responsibility of the Federal Electoral Commission in Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Supervision of polling","Compilation of electoral register","Delimitation of constituencies","Swearing in of member of the House of Assembly"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The structural adjustment programme was introduced by the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Babangida regime","Abacha regime","Murtala\/Obasanjo regime","Buhari regime"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The doctrine of separation of powers is associated with<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Montesquieu","Locke","Marx","Hobbes"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The pressure group that resorts to unconventional methods to achieve its objectives is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["anomic group","institutional group","promotional group","interest group"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A government by people with pride of birth is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["democracy","aristocracy","autocracy","monarchy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Association whose main interest is to influence public policies without having to capture political power are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Pressure groups","Trade unions","Political parties","Professional groups"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Government by the wealthy is known as&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Plutocracy","Democracy","Oligarchy","Aristocracy"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The citizenship of a country could be acquired through<\/strong><\/p>","options":["presidential proclamation","parliamentary legislation","registration arbitration","birth and naturalization"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Eastern and Western regions of Nigeria achieved the status of self development in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1950","1957","1959","1955"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Leaders who superheaded the transformation of the Organization of African Unity into African union were from<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nigeria, Libya and South Africa","Nigeria, Liberia and Morocco","South Africa, Libya and Zambia","Nigeria, Libya and Kenya"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The atomic bomb tests carried out around the Sahara Desert made Nigeria severe relations with<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Canada","Germany","France","Britain"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The first federal constitution in Nigeria was the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Clifford's Constitution","Macpherson's Constitution","Lyttleton Constitution","Independent Constitution"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Judicial administration, the term 'the Bench' refers to the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Judges","Lawyers","Registrars","Litigants"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>A non-monarchical state can be described as a&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Confederation","Republic","Federation","Monarchy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the first Republic of Nigeria, the official opposition party was the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["National Council of Nigeria and Cameroon","Northern Elements Progressive Union","Northern People's Congress","Action Group"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following states is not a member of the African Union (AU)?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Angola","Egypt","Spain","South Africa"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Africa became the centre-piece of Nigerian foreign policy under the regime of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tafawa Balewa","Yakubu Gowon","Shehu Shagari","Murtala Mohammed"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following countries was forced out of the Common wealth of Nations in 1961 for her racial policies?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sri Lanka","South Africa","Nigeria","Republic of Ireland"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Census Crisis of 1962\/63 was caused by the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Revenue Allocation Formula","1960 Independence election","Gross irregularities and inflation of figures by the census officers","Awolowo's move for a socialist Nigeria"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sovereign state is one<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Whose constitution can only be changed by a military government","Where its citizens can speak without fear or favour","In which sovereignty is invested in the military","Whose government decisions are made independent of sovereign interference"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a presssure group in Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Farmers","The Nigerian Union of Teachers (NUT)","The catholic church","Academic Staff Union of Universities (ASUU)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these statements is CORRECT about Proportional Representation?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It makes the assembly representative of all citizens","it is simple to operate","it preserves the party system","it gives the parties seats in proportion to their popular support"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following was NOT the responsibility of the Federal Electoral Commission in Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Supervision of polling","Compilation of electoral register","Delimitation of constituencies","Swearing in of member of the Houses of Assembly"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A historic feature of the Legislature Council that met in 1923 was that for the first time it&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Included official members who were Nigerians","Included only British officials","Acted in a deliberative capacity","Included elected African members"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 1953 motion that Nigeria should be independent in 1956 was moved by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chief Anthony Enahoro","Sir Ahmadu Bello","Chief Obafemi Awolowo","Dr. Nnamdi Azikiwe"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Aristocracy is the system of government in which the few rule for<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Their own benefit","The benefit of all","The benefit of their friends","The benefit of a few"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>An important advantage of creating more constituent units in a federal state is to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Enhance the people's participation in government","Enable ambitious politicians gain political power","Make the state gain more power","Curb the powers of the federal government"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following ethnic groups had centralised administration in pre-colonial Nigeria?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ibibio","Ijaw","Tiv","Hausa"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Judges in Nigeria enjoy security of tenure<\/strong><\/p>","options":["If they are appointed by the president","If they have support of Nigerian Bar Association","If they are of good behaviour","During the life of the government which appoints them"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>According to 1976 Local Government reforms, the chief executive of a local government council is the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Supervisory councilor","Chairman of the local government council","Governor of the state","Secretary of the local government council"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The five permanent members of the United Nations Security council are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["China, U.K., U.S.S.R., U.S.A., and France.","U.S.S.R., Germany, Canada, India and China","U.K., France , U.S.A., Brazil and Ethiopia","U.S.A., China, Liberia, U.S.S.R. and Italy"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The headquarters of the Economic Commission of Africa is located in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ghana","Kenya","Nigeria","Ethiopia"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A common feature of the 1963 and 1979 constitutions is the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Registration of political parties by FEDECO","Financing of the local governments by the Federal government","Judicial Service Commission","Bicameral legislature for the central government"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The doctrine of separation of powers is associated with<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Montesquieu","Locke","Marx","Hobbes"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Delegation is necessary because&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the parliament has enough time","the parliament has all the expertise","some bills are technical in nature","some bills are easy to handle"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The law of libel limits a citizen's right of freedom of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["association","movement","worship","expression"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Voting at elections in Nigeria is limited to ages&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["21 and above","20 and above","19 and above","18 and above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of these is not necessary for a dynamic foreign policy<\/strong><\/p>","options":["political stability","military capability","mass party","economic stability"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria's trade agreement with Zambia is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["multi-lateral relation","bi-lateral relation","mass relations","cordial relations"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>NEPAD was adopted during the OAU summit held in July 2001 at<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Abuja, Nigeria","Cairo, Egypt","Tunis, Tunisia","Lusaka, Zambia"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the these diplomats has represented Nigeria at the United Nations<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chief Aja Nwachukwu","Dr. Joseph Wayas","Major-General Joseph N. Garba","Chief H. O. Davies"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>As a member of O.A.U's good offices committee, Nigeria mediated in the dispute between<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Kenya and Zambia","Ethiopia and Somalia","Tunisia and Morocco","Zimbabwe and Tanzania"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria became a member of the Organization for Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["July, 1961","July, 1971","July, 1981","July, 1991"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The ten non-permanent members of the Security Council are elected by the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Trusteeship Council","Economic and Social Council","General Assembly","United Nation High Commission for Refugees"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of these is NOT a professional pressure group&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Academic Staff Union of Universities","Nigerian Medical Association","Nigerian Bar Association","Nigerian Chamber of Commerce"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The grade\/cadre of the Civil Service closest to the Minister is the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Technical grade\/cadre","Executive grade\/cadre","Administrative grade\/cadre","Clerical grade\/cadre"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In pre-colonial Nigeria, the Northern Emir did NOT use one of these as his head official<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the Talakawa","the Waziri","the Madawaki","the Galadima"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who among these did not take part in the early struggle for Nigeria Indepedence?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chief Osita Agwuna","Professor Ikenna Nzimiro","Joseph Wayas","Ernest Sisei Ikoli"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 1963 constitution in Nigeria is known as the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Presidential Constitution","Independence Constitution","Republican Constitution","Federal Constitution"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A limited geographical territory with a population and sovereign authority is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["society","community","state","government"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In British Parliamentary System, the Monarch can be referred to as the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Queen in parliament","Queen and parliament","Queen's parliament","Queen's assembly"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A government by people with pride of birth is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["democracy","aristocracy","autocracy","monarchy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Nigeria, representations of states in the upper House is based on<\/strong><\/p>","options":["population","ethnicity","equity","equality"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which organ of government is referred to as the last hope of the common man?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the legislature","the parliament","the executive","the judiciary"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A Unitary system of Government leads to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["too much expenditure","duplication of resources","delay in passage of bills","quick passage of bills"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In parliamentary system, powers of the organs of governement are&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["diffused","separated","fused","divided"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Fascism is associated with:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Carl Marx","Benito Mussolini","Adolf Hitler","Mao Tseng Tung"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A written Constitution must contain a&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["dialogue","prologue","preamble","discourse"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Checks and Balances empower the Judiciary to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["interpret the constitution","apply the law","declare null and void actions of other organs","execute the law"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a Parliamentary System, a no confidence vote leads to the resignation of the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["entire cabinet","prime minister","individual minister","entire parliament"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bill can become law only after the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["final reading","presidential assent","third reading","committee stage"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria's foreign policy is basically guided by her maintaining<\/strong><\/p>","options":["permanent friends","permanent interest","permanent cooperation","permanent partners"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The atomic energy tests carried out around the Sahara Desert made Nigeria severe diplomatic relations with<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Canada","United Kingdom","United States of America","France"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>NEPAD is the abbreviation for<\/strong><\/p>","options":["New Peace for Africa's Development","New Programme for Africa's Development","New Partnership for Africa's Development","New Prospect for Africa's Development"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"}]